<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright (c) 2014-2017 Wind River Systems, Inc.

SPDX-License-Identifier: Apache-2.0

-->
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:linkend="http://www.w3.org/1999/linkend"
    xmlns:xref="http://www.w3.org/1999/xref"
    xmlns:wadl="http://wadl.dev.java.net/2009/02"
    version="5.0-extension RackBook-2.0" xml:id="cgcs-rest-overview-v1"
    role="api-reference">
    <title>Titanium Cloud REST API Overview</title>
    <para>The Wind River Systems Titanium Cloud is a high-performance, high-availability, NFV-enabled cloud operating platform that enables telecommunication and industrial operators to deploy and maintain next generation communication services.  It brings together the flexibility and scalability of the IT cloud, and the high-availability and performance demanded by these industry verticals, into a unique industry-leading solution.  The CG Comms Server leverages the power of Commercial Off-The-Shelf (COTS) server hardware to deliver a price-performance ratio well above alternative solutions.</para>
    <para>The Titanium Cloud Platform leverages core Wind River virtualization and carrier-grade technologies, Intel DPDK high-performance packet processing, open architectures, cutting edge security features, and the OpenStack software suite. It extends the OpenStack software suite to implement a unique carrier-grade, high-availability architecture, on which high-performance production systems can be deployed.</para>
    <section xml:id="cgcs-rest-overview-openstack-v1">
        <title>OpenStack REST API Documentation</title>
        <para>The OpenStack REST API Documentation is open-source; both the published formats (PDF and HTML pages) as well as the docbook/wadl source documents.  The published formats can be found at http://developer.openstack.org/api-ref.html .</para>
        <para>Although some of the general open-source OpenStack Documentation (e.g. Admin Guide) is versioned based on OpenStack Releases (e.g. Havana), the open-source OpenStack REST API Documentation is currently NOT versioned.  There is only a master/current version of the OpenStack REST API Documentation containing updates from 'all' versions of OpenStack.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="cgcs-rest-overview-strategy-v1">
        <title>Strategy for Titanium Cloud REST API Documentation</title>
        <para>Due to the lack of versioning on the open-source OpenStack REST API Documentation, Titanium Cloud REST API Documentation will not build on top of open-source documents.  Instead, Titanium Cloud REST API Documenation will provide a description of the delta between the Titanium Cloud REST API and the open-source OpenStack REST API.  For existing OpenStack Components (e.g. Nova, Neutron, ...), any modified APIs will be re-documented with any modified or additional request parameters, response attributes and/or behaviour.  For any new Titanium Components (e.g. SysInv), all APIs will be fully documented.</para>
        <para>Additionally, only high-level description of the semantics around objects and parameters are described in this REST API Documentation.  For full description of objects and parameters, please refer to the Wind River Titanium Cloud Administration Guide.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="cgcs-rest-overview-extensions-v1">
        <title>Titanium-specific Extensions and Titanium REST API Header</title>
        <para>By default, Titanium Cloud does not send 'Titanium Cloud'-specific extensions (attributes) as a part of any REST API responses. In order to have 'Titanium Cloud'-specific extended attributes appear in the REST API responses, the Titanium Cloud header 'wrs-header' must be present in the REST API request. As a result, vanilla Openstack clients will not get any 'Titanium Cloud'-specific  extended attributes as a part of the REST API response. Titanium Cloud clients will automatically send the Titanium Cloud header, and thus contain 'Titanium Cloud'-specific extensions as a part of the REST API response. The components affected by the Titanium Cloud header are Compute, Networking, and Block Storage.</para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="cgcs-rest-overview-sections-v1">
        <title>Overview of Document</title>
        <para>The sections of this document consist of:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>TITANIUM-Extensions to Compute REST API</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>TITANIUM-Extensions to Networking REST API</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>TITANIUM-Extensions to Block Storage REST API</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>TITANIUM-Extensions to Telemetry REST API</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>TITANIUM-Extensions to Image REST API</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>TITANIUM System Inventory (SysInv) REST API</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>TITANIUM Patching REST API</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>There are no TITANIUM-Extensions to Identity REST API (Keystone) and Orchestration REST API (Heat).</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
